Register to The Ernest Trow Carter Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Ernest Trow Carter Papers
1879-1974
MSS 40
Yale University Music Library
18
(44 boxes)
Music, correspondence, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer, conductor, and organist Ernest Trow Carter (1866-1953)
Carter, Ernest, 1866-1953
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Ernest Trow Carter Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University in 1983 by Carter's grandchildren, Edward L. Richards, Jr., Ernest C. Richards, and Laura L. Robertson.
Arrangement
In 11 series as follows: I. Music by Carter. II. Music arranged by Carter. III. Music by others. IV. Production materials. V. Correspondence. VI. Programs. VII. Clippings, press notices, and advertisements. VIII. Photographs. IX. Writings. X. Bills, receipts, contracts, and certificates. XI. Memorabilia.
Scope and Contents
The Ernest Trow Carter Papers contain sketches, manuscript scores, and published editions of Carter's musical compositions, including operas, orchestral works, chamber music, keyboard pieces, choral music, and songs. The Papers also contain music composed by others and arranged by Carter. The correspondence includes letters to and from Carter and performers, composers, publishers, musical organizations, and family members. Carter's life and work are further documented by: production materials; programs; clippings; photographs; writings by and about Carter; and financial records and memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Ernest Trow Carter was born in Orange, New Jersey, on September 3, 1866. He graduated from Princeton University cum laude in 1888. Carter earned an M.A. in law from Columbia University in 1899, and would later receive an honorary Doctor of Music degree from Princeton in 1932.
While at Princeton, Carter led the Glee Club and Chapel Choir, and composed and arranged music for these groups. In 1892 he became musical director of the Thacher School in Ojai, California. Two years later he moved to Berlin to study composition and organ. Upon returning to the United States, Carter resumed his organ studies. He also served as lecturer in music, organist, and choirmaster at Princeton from 1899 to 1901. His interest in composition led him to resign from this position, and during the next year he sang in the Metropolitan Opera Chorus in order to study opera technique.
Carter composed works for orchestra, band, chorus, and keyboard, as well as songs, chamber and instrumental music, and stage works. The three major stage works include two operas, The Blonde Donna and The White Bird, and a ballet-pantomime, Namba. Carter himself wrote the libretto for The Blonde Donna. It premiered in concert form in New York in February 1912. The first full performance was by the New York Opera Comique at the Brooklyn Little Theater on December 8, 1931. The White Bird, composed to a libretto by Brian Hooker, placed second among eighteen entries in the Hinshaw Contest of 1916-1917. Its first performance, also in concert form, was at Carnegie Chamber Music Hall on May 23, 1922, with Carter conducting. The first full performance of The White Bird was at the Studebaker Theater, in Chicago, on March 6, 1924. The Opera in Our Language Foundation sponsored the performance, and awarded Carter the first David Bispham Memorial Medal. On November 15, 1927, The White Bird became the first American opera to be performed at the Municipal Theater of Osnabrück, Germany. Namba was first presented at the Columbus School for Girls in May, 1924, and later performed by the Charlotte Lund Opera Company and the Aleta Doré Ballet at the Shakespeare Theater of New York, on April 22, 1933.
Ernest Trow Carter died in Stamford, Connecticut, on June 21, 1953.
Bartholomew, Marshall, 1885-1978; Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946; Carter, Ernest, 1866-1953; Craft, Marcella, 1874-1959; Damrosch, Frank, 1859-1937; Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950; Deis, Carl, 1883-1960; Devriès, Hermann, 1858-1949; Dippel, Johann Andreas, 1866-1932; Doré, Aleta; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955; Freer, Eleanor Everest, 1864-1942; Garden, Mary, 1874-1967; Goldman, Edwin Franko, 1878-1956; Hadley, Henry, 1871-1937; Hageman, Richard, 1881-1966; Hamlin, George John, 1868-1923; Henderson, W. J. (William James), 1855-1937; Herzog, Sigmund, 1868-1932; Hibben, John Grier, 1861-1933; Hinshaw, William Wade, 1867-1947; Hooker, Brian, 1880-1946; Hutcheson, Ernest, 1871-1951; Johnson, Horace, 1893-1964; Judson, Arthur, 1881-1975; Kahn, Otto H., 1867-1934; Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969; La Forge, Frank, 1879-1953; La Liberté, Alfred, 1878-1953; Lilienthal, Abraham Wolf, 1859-1928; Mason, William, 1829-1908; McCormick, Cyrus H. (Cyrus Hall), 1859-1936; Nevin, Arthur, 1871-1943; Polacco, Giorgio, 1873-1960; Reese, Gustave, 1899-1977; Rogers, Francis, 1870-1951; Saenger, Gustav, 1865-1935; Schirmer, Rudolph Edward, 1859-1919; Svečenski, Louis, 1862-1926; Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946; Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966; Tibbett, Lawrence, 1896-1960; Welch, Roy Dickinson, 1885-1951; Witherspoon, Herbert, 1873-1935; Gatti-Casazza, Giulio, 1869-1940
- Music by Carter, 1879-1968; Series I; 13.75' (33 boxes)
  General
  This series includes holograph, manuscript, printed, and published music by Carter. The music is divided into nine subseries by genre (A-I). Within each subseries, the works are arranged alphabetically by title. Uniform titles are used to bring together all of the manifestations of a work with various titles. Cross references appear in the index from other forms of a title to the uniform title, between an original work and its arrangements, and for those pieces which are included with another work.
  Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the entire series, with the exception of one oversized box housed at the end of the collection (Box 44).
  Subseries I, Carmina Princetonia, includes Princeton songbooks containing music by or arranged by Carter.
  - Opera and Stage Works, I.A
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([455] p. in various pagings); 34 cm. (Box 01, Folder 1-5)
      Holograph, signed, and manuscript in Otto Fessler's hand in ink with pencil additions
      Opera in three acts
      Words by Carter
      At end of overture: Otto Fessler May - 1932
      Revised version (1945) of Act I, Scene 2, no. 13 laid in
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([292] sheets in various pagings); 35-39 cm. (Box 01, Folder 6-10)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy)
      Song for Tellacus, Piastro, and Female Chorus. 9 sheets, photocopy with note by Carter, omitted by Halton, laid in
      Note on old envelope: Photostat (positives) orchestra score as used by Halton, numbered 1 to 20 (plus I, 11, Tellacus, Piastro + women)
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna / Ernest Carter. -- 1931 Oct., 1 manuscript score ([589] sheets in various pagings); 33 cm. (Box 02, Folder 11-24)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy, negative)
      Sheets with notes by Carter laid in score
      Sheet laid in front of score contains note: ...these were made in Oct. 1931...
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna / Ernest Carter. -- 1936 Feb.-Aug., 5 manuscript parts; 33 cm. (Box 03, Folder 25-29)
      manuscript in ink in Otto Fessler's hand
      Dates from bottom corners of parts
      Note on folder containing vln. I part: These 5 string parts by Fessler not used at Redlands nor corrected for that production
      Note on old folder: Missing Ten Men + (seems to be there) Oct. 29/40
      Includes vln. I-II, vla., vlc., and d.b. parts
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna / by Ernest Carter. -- 1910-1915., 44 manuscript parts; 34 cm. (Box 03, Folder 30-32)
      Holographs, in part, signed in ink with pencil additions
      Miscellaneous orchestral parts, labeled "extra"
    - [Blonde donna] The Blonde Donna. -- 1910-1915., 21 manuscript parts; 35 cm. (Box 04; 05, Folder 33-40; 41-46)
      manuscript in ink
      Dates from lower left corners of parts
      Orchestral parts
    - [Blonde donna] 1910-1911., 35 manuscript parts; 17-34 cm. (Box 06, Folder 47)
      Holographs and manuscript in ink
      Miscellaneous vocal parts
    - [Blonde donna] Blonde Donna. -- 1911-1934., 38 manuscript parts; 20-36 cm. (Box 06, Folder 48-51)
      manuscript in ink with pencil notes
      Miscellaneous vocal parts, some duplicates
    - [Blonde donna. Angelus hymn with "America." Vocal score] The Angelus Hymn with "America": from The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera comique in three acts / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- 1941 Jun., 1 manuscript vocal score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 06, Folder 52)
      Holograph, signed, in ink
      Note laid in: Exhibited Los Angeles, 1941
      See also: Correspondence, NAACC
    - [Blonde donna. Aria (Señora Blanca). Vocal score] Aria Señora Blanca: From The Blonde Donna / By Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score ([2] p.); 33 cm. (Box 06, Folder 52)
      manuscript in pencil
    - [Blonde donna. Bonifacio (Melodrama). Libretto] Bonifacio (Melodrama)., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 06, Folder 52)
      Typescript with notes by Carter
    - [Blonde donna. Chorus score] The Blonde Donna / Ernest Carter. -- c1911., 1 manuscript chorus score (28 p.); 25 cm. (Box 07, Folder 53)
      manuscript (photocopy)
      Seven copies with notes and corrections by Carter, one copy from envelope marked as used in Opera Comique
    - [Blonde donna. Chorus score], 1 manuscript score (12 p.); 28 cm. (Box 07, Folder 54)
      For tenors and basses
      Two copies
    - [Blonde donna. Chorus score], 1 manuscript score (12 p.); 28 cm. (Box 07, Folder 54)
      For sopranos and altos
    - [Blonde donna. Dress chorus. Vocal score] No. 4. Chorus of Women., 1 manuscript vocal score (sheets 81-88); 36 cm. (Box 07, Folder 55)
      Holograph (photocopy, negative)
      On old envelope: No. 4. Act I. Scene 2
    - [Blonde donna. Dress chorus. Vocal score] Dress Chorus: For Female Voices / Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1907 Nov. 20., 1 manuscript vocal score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 07, Folder 55)
      Date from bottom of first p.
    - [Blonde donna. Finale 1. Vocal score] Fortsetzung: Finale 1 / Halton., 1 manuscript vocal score (pp. 52-59); 34 cm. (Box 07, Folder 56)
      Holograph in ink
    - [Blonde donna. Glee. Vocal score] Glee: (The Padres): No. 8, b + c. -- 1931 May 5., 1 manuscript vocal score (pp. 150-151); 35 cm. (Box 07, Folder 57)
      Holograph in ink with pencil notes
      Note: omit in Jones version May 5/31
    - [Blonde donna. Have no fear, Señorita] No. 2, Act II / Ernest Carter. -- 1911 Mar. 4-8., 1 manuscript score (13 p.) + 18 parts; 35 cm. (Box 07, Folder 58)
      Holographs (score signed), in ink
      Parts dated in lower left corners: 1911 Mar 4-8
    - [Blonde donna. I used to be a saucy don] No. 5A - "Song" - Tellacus: Act II insert / Ernest Carter., 17 manuscript parts; 31 cm. (Box 07, Folder 59)
      Note on old envelope: used by Opera Comique as II6
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] Lyrics from The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: a romantic comic opera in three acts / by Ernest Carter. -- c1907., 22 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 07, Folder 60)
      Typescript (photocopy) with notes by Carter
      Note on old envelope: Shown to Victor Herbert in March, 1908
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Romantic comic opera in four acts / words and music by Ernest Carter. -- c1907-1911., 29, 33, 32, 16 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 07, Folder 61)
      Two copies, note on cover of one copy: old version
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique / words and music by Ernest Carter. -- 1907-1926., 113 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 07, Folder 62)
      Note on cover: Old - marked for revision summer 1926
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in Three Acts / words and music by Ernest Carter. -- 1907-1934., 83 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 07, Folder 63)
      Typescript with pencil additions
      Three copies
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in Three Acts / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- 1907-1934., 74 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 07, Folder 64)
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera comique in three acts / by Ernest Carter; the German adaptation and translation by Theo Halton; of which the following is a rough re-translation into English by Ernest Carter. -- 1929., A, 72 sheets; 32 cm. (Box 08, Folder 65)
      Holograph in ink with pencil additions
      Note on old envelope: summer of 1929
      Photocopy laid in
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in three acts / by Ernest Carter; the German adaptation and translation by Theo Halton; of which the following is a rough re-translation into English by Ernest Carter. -- c1930., 70 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 08, Folder 66)
      Typescript
      Three copies, labeled "1st set" and "2nd set - shorter hist. note"
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in Three Acts / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1932., vi, 41 p.; 25 cm. (Box 08, Folder 67)
      Three marked copies, with changes dating from 1937 to 1941
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto] ca. 1936 Jan. 21., 29 parts; 18 x 23 cm. (Box 08, Folder 68)
      Individual dialogue parts, some marked "original #2," others "copy #2"
      On old envelope: am sending 14 originals to Mrs. Morris Jan. 21/36
      Contains pencil additions by Carter
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto. German] Die blonde Donna: Singspiel in drei Akten / von Ernest Carter; Deutshe [sic] Bearbeitung von Theo Halton. -- ca. 1927 Aug., [1], 36, 33, 23 sheets; 29 cm. (Box 08, Folder 69)
      Contains pencil additions and note laid in by Carter
      Correction dated 1927 Aug
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto. German] Die blonde Donna: oder das Fest von Danta [sic] Barbara: Komische Oper / Worte und Musik von Ernest Carter. -- [1927]., 81 sheets; 29 cm. (Box 08, Folder 70)
      Typescript (photocopy)
      Note by Carter on old envelope: 1st translation into German by Frau Babs (thru van der Floe) 1927
      Note by Carter on title page: van der Floe had this first translation made by Frau Babs (quite sure that was the name) E.C.
      Contains notes by Carter
      Two copies, title page and sheets 1-4 missing from one copy
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto. German] Die blonde Donna: Singspeil in drei Akten / von Ernest Carter; Deutshe [sic] Bearbeitung von Theo Halton., [1], 36, 33, 24 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 08, Folder 71)
    - [Blonde donna. Libretto. German] "Die blonde Donna": Singspiel in drei Akten / von Ernest Carter., [1], 35, 33, 24 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 08, Folder 72)
    - [Blonde donna. Of maidens I've seen quite a score] No. 4 - Act II, Scene 2: Scene Marinus and Genio. -- 1914 Oct. 16., 1 manuscript score (4 p.) + 17 parts; 34 cm. (Box 09, Folder 73)
      Holographs (parts signed) in ink
      On title page: Discarded - see copy in G
      Parts dated 1914 Oct. 16
    - [Blonde donna. Oh no, we are not thirsty. Vocal score] No. 2: Female chorus: "Oh no, we are not thirsty." -- 1931 May 2., 1 manuscript vocal score (sheet 18); 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 74)
      Note: Omit for Jones version May 2/31
    - [Blonde donna. Overture] The Blonde Donna: Overture / by Ernest Carter. -- 1910-1913., 1 manuscript score (35 p.) + 15 parts; 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 75)
      Holographs, signed, in ink with pencil additions
      Note on title page: Complete for 2 flutes, 1 oboe, 2 clarinets, 1 bassoon, 2 horns, 2 trumpets, bass trombone, timpani + strings - Later added II + IV horns + I + II trombones, II oboe and II bassoon
      Note on old envelope: score + extra parts
      Dates appear in lower left corners of parts
    - [Blonde donna. Scene (Second day, morning). Vocal score] Act III, Scene 1: Second Day, morning: No. 1. Prelude., 1 manuscript vocal score (pp. 114-115); 34 cm. (Box 09, Folder 76)
      Holograph in ink with pencil markings
      Note on first p.: Dropped May 4/31 to shorten
    - [Blonde donna. Selections] 1912-1915., [100] p. in various pagings; 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 77)
      Holographs and manuscript, in part signed, in ink with pencil additions
      Note on old folder: Discarded numbers
      Dates from bottom left corners of parts
    - [Blonde donna. Selections], 19, 7, [5] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 78)
      Holographs in ink and pencil
      Includes: Finale 1, Finale 2, Gypsy dance, Quintet, and Act III Finale (negative photocopies laid in)
      Note on old envelope: orchestra score - Halton Finales 1 + 2 - orig. manuscript + photo. negs. + other pages - also blank sheets + slips to cover parts of pages
    - [Blonde donna. Selections (Sketches)] [13] p. of music; 8-35 cm., Holographs in ink and pencil (Box 09, Folder 79)
    - [Blonde donna. Selections. Vocal score] [ca. 1936 Aug. 10], [13] p. of music; 38 cm. (Box 09, Folder 80)
      Holograph (photocopy)
      Pencil note by Carter: These pages were removed before delivery of remainder to C + C Music Printing Co., Aug. 10, 1936
    - [Blonde donna. Serenade] Act I, Scene 2. No. 16: Serenade: male quartet: Marinus, a second tenor, Genio, and a second bass / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (11 p.); 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 81)
      On title page: old copy
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara / Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1910 Oct. 25., 1 manuscript vocal score (215 [i.e. 212] p.); 35 cm. (Box 09, Folder 82)
      Holograph, signed, in part manuscript, in ink with pencil additions
      Lists of musical numbers (3 sheets) laid in
      Date appears on bottom of title page
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara / Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1910-1931, 1 manuscript vocal score (259 [i.e. 253] p.); 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 83-84)
      Holograph, signed, in ink with pencil additions
      Score contains dates from 1910-1915
      Note on p. 173: pp. 174-80 cut by Jones, 1926
      On old envelope: manuscript piano score by Lib-? from which photostats made and marked by Thomas + me 1931
      No. 13. Chorus (pp. 115-117) laid in
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in Three Acts / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1936 Sep. - Nov., 1 manuscript vocal score (239 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 10, Folder 85-87)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy), with red and blue pencil additions
      Note on old envelope: used by C + C Music Printing Corp. + returned to me Dec. 5/36 but not examined E.C.
      Notes on score dated 1936 Sep. - Nov.
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara: Opera Comique in Three Acts / Words and Music by Ernest Carter. -- New York: The Composers Press, Inc., c1936., 1 vocal score ([2], 200 p.), bound; 32 cm. (Box 10, Folder 88-89)
      Two copies, one which contains markings and a list headed "Books out" laid in
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna / Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score (4 v.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 90-93)
      Includes corrections and additions by Carter
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: piano score., 1 manuscript vocal score (4 v.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 12, Folder 94-97)
      Note on p.1: Marked by Thomas
      Note on old envelope: rec'd from Kendall Muzzy est. after death in 1942
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score] The Blonde Donna: or The Fiesta of Santa Barbara / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score (4 v.), bound; 37 cm. (Box 13, Folder 98-101)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy), with pencil additions
      Note: This copy was marked by Rudolph Thomas
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score. German & English] The Blonde Donna: opera comique / book lyrics and music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score (240 [i.e. 194] p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 102)
    - [Blonde donna. Vocal score. German] Die Blonde Donna: Singspiel in 3 Akten / von Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript vocal score (149 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - [Namba] Namba: or The Third Statue / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (87 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 104)
      Ballet-pantomime for orchestra and chorus ad lib.
      Words not included
    - [Namba] Namba: or The Third Statue / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (87 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 105)
      Holograph, signed (photocopy) with pencil additions by Carter
    - [Namba] Namba: or The Third Statue / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (87 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - [Namba] ca. 1929 Nov. - Dec., 19 manuscript parts; 14-34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 107)
      Holographs, in part signed, and manuscript in ink and pencil
      [3] sheets of notes laid in, two list "parts for orchestra of 30"
      Dates in lower left corners of parts
      Pencil note on most parts: used Apr. 22/33 and Dec. 27/33
    - [Namba] Namba / Ernest Carter., 7 manuscript parts; 27 cm. (Box 14, Folder 108)
      Holographs, signed, in ink and pencil
      Old envelope: parts for orchestra of 12
    - [Namba] ca. 1924-1934., 8 manuscript parts; 26-35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 109)
      Holographs, signed, in ink
      Notes ([2] sheets) laid in with list of "Parts for orchestra of 12"
      Note on old folder: Old for Columbus
    - [Namba; arr.] Namba: or The Third Statue: Ballet Pantomime / Music by Ernest Carter; Adapted from an Arabian Nights Tale by Grace Latimer McClure., 1 manuscript piano score (31 p.) + 1 part; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Arr. for piano and chorus ad lib.
      Chorus part on page 32
    - [Namba; arr.] Namba: The Third Statue / [music by] Ernest Carter; [words adapted by] Grace Latimer Jones McClure., 1 manuscript piano score (26 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 111)
      Ballet-pantomime arr. for piano and chorus ad lib.
      Chorus part at end of score
      Positive and negative photocopies laid in
    - [Namba; arr.] Namba: or The Third Statue / Music by Ernest Carter; Scenario from an Arabian Nights' Tale by [Grace McClure]., 1 manuscript piano score (23 sheets); 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 112)
      Holograph, signed, in pencil
      Sheets 3a-3c laid in
    - [What makes Christmas Christmas] What makes Christmas Christmas: (Incidentals Song of "A Spirit") / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Grace Latimer Jones McClure. -- c1926., 1 manuscript score (6 p.) + 1 part; 25-34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 113)
      For solo voices, bells, and piano
      Includes bells part
      Sheet listing dates music was sent to certain people laid in
    - [What makes Christmas Christmas] What Makes Christmas Christmas: (Incidentals song of "A Spirit") / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Grace Latimer Jones., 1 manuscript score (7 p.) + 1 part; 26-34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 113)
    - [What makes Christmas Christmas] What Makes Christmas Christmas: Songs of "The Spirit" / Words by Grace Latimer Jones; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 113)
    - [What makes Christmas Christmas] What Makes Christmas Christmas: (Incidental Songs of "A Spirit") / [music by] Ernest Carter. -- 1922 Nov., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 33 cm. (Box 14, Folder 113)